I want to study but my desire
to have fun makes it hard.
I let my desires dictate and
I don't get things done.
So in trying to control my desires,
I end up hating my own desires.
For example, when I want to have fun,
I would force myself
to think about studying.
When I want to hang out with my friends,
I would tell myself 'No'.
Then, I end up hating my own desires and
my life has become rather constricted.
So, I am curious and want to ask
if it's OK to hate my desires,
or if I need to live differently.
It's not very specific
Are you saying that
it is difficult to repress your desire
for fun in order to study?
(Questioner) Not difficult but
I hate my own desires..
You hate your mind wanting to have fun?
(Questioner) Yes.
If you want to have fun,
just go ahead and play.
(Audience Laughter)
(Questioner) Then I won't be
able to achieve my goal.
What is your goal?
(Questioner) Studying.
Studying?
(Audience Laughter)
(Questioner) Yes
I would like to be real smart.
Then you can make studying fun.
Study like you are playing.
What is fun for you?
Sometimes you like to drink?
(Questioner) Yes.
Then, study while you're drinking.
(Audience Laughter)
(Questioner) Ah...
Then, study while you're drinking.
(Questioner) Yes.
If you want to date, you and
your girlfriend can study together.
You can meet at the library
and study together.
If you want to go out drinking,
you can discuss some study subjects
while you're drinking.
This way, you can do both:
studying and having fun.
Yes, I think you are right. Thank you.
(Audience Laughter)
Yes.
Hold on to the microphone.
I do these lectures as if I am playing.
This is fun, isn't it?
(Audience Laughter)
People ask me how I can give
3-4 lectures a day.
Once, I gave 5 lectures in one day.
One day a man came to ask me
for a lecture.
Usually, I give 2-3 lectures
but that day I had 4 scheduled already.
But the man asked me to give a lecture
on that day.
My office staff told him at least 10 times
that I could not. But he kept insisting.
When I returned from US, he was waiting
for me at the airport. He asked me again.
He said 300 students were coming so it
would be disastrous if I didn't show up.
I showed him my itinerary.
I said, "it's not that I don't want to"
"My schedule is full."
"I don't have the time."
"But if you insist, I can come at 10:30
or 11 pm after other lectures."
He looked over my itinerary, then said
"Could you still do it then?"
So, I agreed.
(Audience Laughter)
But I thought, "Who would come
at 11 pm, especially students.."
Not even older folks, but 300 students?
So, I asked if they'd really show up,
he said yes.
I thought something was rather odd
about this organization.
Unless it was a religious group,
how can they gather 300 students
at 11 pm?
I agreed to it, but was thinking that
he would cancel later.
But no cancellation.
(Sunim) So, I went at 11 pm.
There were about 50 people when I arrived.
(Laughter)
I lectured until 12:30.
I lectured as if there were 500 people.
People think it must be hard for me
to keep up with my schedule.
If I were getting paid for my lectures,
it would be.
If a company made someone work that much,
they would be sued for labor exploitation.
If I'd thought of it as a job, I would
have been exhausted and quit already.
But I do it for fun. I am fine
because I take it as playing.
So how should you study?
Take studying as playing
"You may not think so, but it's true.
Analyzing it psychologically,
Let's say some people are on stage
and the rest are down there.
Psy's music starts playing and
everyone starts dancing and singing.
People down there paid $30
to get in to dance.
People on the stage got paid $300
to dance.
Did the people down there come to
play or work?
What about the people on the stage?
They came to work, right?
The schedule said one hour, but if it were
extended by another 30 minutes,
the people down there be happy or not?
What about the people on the stage?
Everyone is dancing and singing, but why
are some playing and others working?
They are all dancing and singing,
but the people down there call it playing
and the people up here call it working.
Right. If you are paid, it's work.
If you pay, it's play.
It's the same for me.
If I get paid for lecturing,
is it work or play?
That's why I don't ask for payment
for my lectures.
If I get paid, this is work.
If I don't, this is play.
So If I got paid for giving 5 lectures
in one day, I would call it hard labor.
Doing this 5 times without pay,
what do we call this?
(Sunim) I say I played until I dropped.
So, don't think that the studying is done
only at the desk.
If you feel like drinking,
have a drink while you study.
If you want a date,
don't pick a girl who only wants to play.
What sort of girl to date?
Pick a girl who wants to study
so you can study while you date.
Study as if it's play.
This way, you won't get so stressed.
Your concentration level becomes higher
when you are enjoying it.
When kids read comic books or play games,
do they concentrate or not?
They are very focused.
They can't even hear their mom calling.
The only way to concentrate well is to
enjoy what you are doing.
But you cannot force yourself
to concentrate.
Concentration can make you to burst out.
Bursting through so to speak.
Insights and creative breakthroughs
can happen.
Creativity is more important from now on.
The era of new creativity is coming.
Educational credentials or knowledge
would not be so important.
The most important skill is the ability
to solve problems and creativity.
During the last century,
it was useful for us to imitate the developed
countries, like the U.S. and Europe.
It was fine for our children
to learn by rote to imitate.
The Western countries were
the developed countries
and we were a third world country.
Catching up with the western countries
became our goal since we were behind.
So, we caught up
and became a developed country.
Now we are close to be in the
first world status, I hear.
That was when the Western countries
were doing well.
But the U.S. and Europe
have reached their limits.
They can't solve their financial crisis.
They have reached the limit
in their cultural dominance.
Now, we have no target to catch up to.
We can either fall with them,
or we can surpass them
by cultivating our own creativity.
When you are imitating,
you succeed 9 out 10.
When you are innovating, you succeed
1 out of 1000. You will fail 999 times.
So, what is necessary?
We need to challenge and take risks.
You can only do it by enjoying the task,
not being stressed out.
If you enjoy hiking, you will keep going
even your legs are tired.
While learning to ride a bike, even though
they fall over and over again,
kids don't give up,
they keep going, right?
If one kid falls 5 times and another
falls 10 times, are they failures?
Or the kid who fell 10 times is getting
close to riding the bike?
He is getting there.
It may sound strange but
to fall is to ride. Make sense?
The more you fall,
the closer you are to success.
So, they say that
failure is the mother of success.
To put it wisely,
"defilement is enlightenment".
Do you understand?
Falling is riding.
The days are gone
when we kept elegant words
like "affliction is enlightenment"
in a temple shelf.
We need to apply them
in our daily lives.
"Ordinary mind is the way of enlightenment."
Have you heard this?
Not by gritting teeth in determination.
By everyday mind, we find the way. So,
studying should be the same..like playing.
Don't pressure yourself by
separating studying and playing
Turn studying into playing, ok?
Make studying fun.
Studying should be more fun
than anything else.
As a parent,
if you want to make studying fun,
you scold your kids when they study.
You bar them from studying.
(Audience Laughter)
Make them work,
reprimand them when they study,
then the kids will want to study.
They would study in secret.
Studying in secret becomes really fun.
In our human history, all those
who studied in secret all succeeded.
Studying secretly indicates that
the desire to study is very strong.
So, they can succeed.
In other words, studying should be fun.
Try to proceed with this attitude.